# **Neng Wang**

wangneng100@gmail.com 8326709815

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Architect/Principle Engineer with 10+ years experience on Enterprise Software. Proficient in system design, data integration, and cloud SaaS/PaaS software development. In-depth knowledge of Data Cleansing, Refining and Integration products. Good experience with Microservices Technologies and Amazon Web Services.

Responsible for product and software architecture, design and lead the implementation. Remains engaged, proactive and positive in tough circumstances, owning assignments and taking full accountability for overall team success.

#### Specialties:

- System Architect, Design and Development. Agile software development
- Data Cleansing/Refining, Integration Cloud, iPaaS, CICD
- Elasticsearch, MySQL, PostgreSQL
- · Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Linkerd, Fluentbit, AKS, EKS, GEK
- Java, Python, Gradle, Maven, Ant
- Spring Boot, REST API's, OAuth2
- JIRA, Confluence, Jenkins, Teamcity
- AWS((Amazon S3, EC2, RDS, EFS, Route53, EKS, Elasticsearch etc.)

### Work EXPERIENCE

## • Architect | TIBCO Software Inc. | Stafford, TX

May

2019 - Present

- Analyze Elasticsearch performance issue, redesign the indices schema and refactory the backend code. Improve the response speed for more than 30%.
- Provide technical expertise and leadership in the design, development, and delivery of TIBCO AuditSafe Enterprise Edition using Spring Boot, Docker, and Kubernetes technologies.
- Design the CI/CD system of TIBCO Business Connector and TIBCO AuditSafe Enterprise Edition with TeamCity.
- Design and implement TIBCO Flogo Connector and BusinessWorks Plugin for TIBCO AuditSafe and TIBCO Clarity.
- Lead developer team to design and develop TIBCO Clarity Cloud and integrate with TIBCO Spotfire and TIBCO EBX.
- Collaborate across teams in brainstorming; review and research top technologies to recommend tools, frameworks, and best practices to improve the stability, performance, and quality of our products.

# Senior Software Engineer | Pactera NA Inc. | Stafford, TX May 2019

Dec 2015 -

- Design and implement TIBCO AuditSafe Cloud.
- Implement the build and deploy system for TIBCO AuditSafe Cloud. Using Gradle, Docker and AWS technologies.
- Designing, Programming for TIBCO Clarity on Cloud. Integration Clairty to TIBCO Cloud and Implement new feature for the product.

- Senior Software Engineer | Pactera Technology Limited | Beijing, China May 2011-Dec 2015
  - Programming, Testing for TCT (Tibco Configuration Tool) with OSGI framework.
  - Programming, Testing for Clarity. Main modules are: Activespaces, MDM, Vaule, Spotfire connector and Cloud Storage. Cloud Storage includes Google Drive, Dropbox, and Box.
  - Demand analysis, Programming, Testing and Files management for Business Event Channels.
- Software Engineer | Taiji Computer Corporation Limited | Beijing, China Jul 2009 -- April 2011
  - Demand analysis, Programming, Testing and Files management for Public Health Emergency Commanding and Decision-Making System of Yunnan Province.
  - Took part in 2010 Health Information Technology Conference in Xiamen and made on-site demonstration.

## **Education**

•	Master Degree in Software Engineering 07/2009	Wuhan University	09/2006 —
•	Master Degree in Telecommunications Engineering 09/2008	Dublin City University	09/2007 —
•	Bachelor Degree in Software Engineering 07/2006	Wuhan University	09/2002 —

#### **Award**

- 2015.2 Model Trainee of Pactera PMA program
- 2013.1 Best Development Group of TIBCO CDC
- 2012.1 Excellent staff of TIBCO CDC
- 2011.1 Excellent staff of Taiji
- 2010.1 Best Development Award Individual Winner